A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release
（男性）ハァ ハァ…
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
ハァ ハァ
Major. Hey, Major!
（バトー）少佐 おい 少佐
l/I/hal' was that'? Virtual reality?
何だ 今の？ 仮想現実か？
（素子(もとこ)）休暇中だ
気安く電脳ロビーに入るな
/'n7 on vacation- Don '1' be so casual
about entering my c yber lobby.
（バトー）ご愁傷さま
My condolences- There's been
a terror/st' bombing in N/'sh/'nouchi.
西ノ内(にしのうち)で爆弾テロ
被害者は外国系水企業の重役
The vies were an executive at
a foreign-owned water company,
産業省役人 国内兵器製造業者
a Trade Ministry official,
and a domestic weapons manufacturer.
少佐が公安に提出した
テロ予測リストの最優先項目が的中
The top-priority entry in
the terrorism prediction list
you gave Public Security
was right on target.
/ assume they were in a secret
meeting to agree on water prices.
（素子）水の価値協定に関する
秘密会議ね
/ assume they were in a secret
meeting to agree on water prices.
Everything's in smithereens,
including some Foreign Affairs guards-
（バトー）
外務省の警備兵ごとバラバラ
Everything's in smithereens,
including some Foreign Affairs guards-
ついでに山(やま)の手(て)のダムでも
爆発があった
There was also an explosion at
the Yamanote Dam, by the Way.
（素子）ダム？
The dam?
（バトー）関連は不明
Dunno if it's related.
ただし 産業省の天下り先で
実質は外国系水企業の持ち物だ
But it essentially belongs to
a foreign-owned water company,
and there's a retired Trade official on staff
The bureaucrats ' turf wars
are intense in that industry.
（素子）官僚同士の縄張り争いが
激しい業界ね
The bureaucrats ' turf wars
are intense in that industry.
で どこが私たちに要請を？
So, who asked for us?
（バトー）毎度の公安９課
Sect/on .9, as usual.
They failed to put your list to good use,
but the y did track the perps-
少佐のリスト活用にしくじるも
実行犯を追跡
They failed to put your list to good use,
but the y did track the perps-
They say they can '1' secure 'em,
though. 7'00 outgunned.
だが 結局 武装の差で
確保できねえとさ
They say they can '1' secure 'em,
though. 7'00 outgunned.
Cal/ everyone in. I'm coming I00.
（素子）全員 呼び出せ 私も行く
（ホセ）仕事かい？
Work calls?
I'm sorry.
（素子）ごめんなさい
Five hours, seven minutes.
That's a record-length vacation for you.
（ホセ）５時間と７分
Five hours, seven minutes.
That's a record-length vacation for you.
君の休暇の最長記録だ
Five hours, seven minutes.
That's a record-length vacation for you.
Are you consulting for the police today?
Or the Cyberbrain Development Bureau?
今日のコンサルトは警察？
Are you consulting for the police today?
Or the Cyberbrain Development Bureau?
それとも電脳開発局？
Are you consulting for the police today?
Or the Cyberbrain Development Bureau?
I'll make it up to you.
（素子）埋め合わせはするわ
Don't forget what we talked about.
（ホセ）例の件 忘れないで
あ… 本気なの？
Are you serious?
（ホセ）もちろん
Of course.
（ホセ）
さっ 早く行ったほうがいい
You should get going. All your
customers are impatient types, right?
気の短い得意先ばかりなんだろう？
You should get going. All your
customers are impatient types, right?
Yes.
Wow, you've been with that guy for
three months! That's a new reooro'.
（バトー）お前 その男と
３か月も続いてるじゃねえか
Wow, you've been with that guy for
three months! That's a new reooro'.
記録更新だな
Wow, you've been with that guy for
three months! That's a new reooro'.
Don't be so casual about using
that Ghost infiltration key.
ゴースト侵入キーを気安く使うな
Don't be so casual about using
that Ghost infiltration key.
Your precinct lD'd him as
Detective Naoharu Mizuki.
（警部補）署に照会したところ
水城(みずき)ナオハル刑事だそうだが―
Your precinct lD'd him as
Detective Naoharu Mizuki.
間違いないか？
Is that right?
（トグサ）ああ 俺の先輩だ
Yeah. He's my senior.
Is this all he had on him?
所持品はこれだけか？
ホルスターが空だった
His holster was empty.
His piece must've been washed away or stolen.
水に流されたか
誰かに盗まれたか…
His piece must've been washed away or stolen.
It's hard to believe the gun under
his jacket would get washed away.
（トグサ）懐の銃が流されるとは
考えにくい
It's hard to believe the gun under
his jacket would get washed away.
財布が無事で
銃だけ取っていくのも変だ
And it'd be odd for someone to
steal his gun but leave his wallet.
A prosthetics specialist...
“義体技師”…
He sure doesn't look cyborgized.
義体化された遺体には見えんな
Lieutenant, your guys rounded up
all the unclaimed property in the area, right?
（トグサ）警部補 周辺の遺失物は
集めて管理してるな？
Lieutenant, your guys rounded up
all the unclaimed property in the area, right?
他に彼につながる物を探す
Let's look for something else
that ties back to him.
You want me to be your errand boy?
（警部補）
使いっ走りに なれってのか？
If the darn incident was really an accident, yes.
ダムの件が本当の事故ならな
（鑑識官）警部補
Lieutenant! I found something odd.
（鑑識官）妙な物を見つけました
What are these?
何だ？ これ
They look like prosthetics, but...
（鑑識官）義体のようですが…
Mermaid's Legs...
（トグサ）人魚の脚…
Report.
（素子）状況は？
Lots of injured cops.
Six perps still going strong.
（バトー）警官に負傷者多数
実行犯６名は健在
Lots of injured cops.
Six perps still going strong.
４区に移動中だ
They're on their way to Ward 4.
They see right through the police strategy.
（パズ）警察の動きを
完全に読んでるな
They see right through the police strategy.
They secured an escape route ahead of time.
（ボーマ）逃走経路を
確保した上での撤退行動
They secured an escape route ahead of time.
This group is highly trained.
相当 訓練を積んだ連中だ
どこかに作戦指揮官がいる
イシカワ
They have a commander
somewhere out there. lshikawa!
/ picked up their line!
（イシカワ）
連中のラインを捉えた
The seventh one. This is their leader.
（素子）７人目 こいつが頭だ
（ゲリラ１）ん！？
This is a cutting-edge ghost lock.
Don't waste time resisting.
（素子）最新のゴーストロックだ
無駄な抵抗はするな
This is a cutting-edge ghost lock.
Don't waste time resisting.
/'// make him order his friends to surrender.
（素子）仲間に投降を命じさせる
lsh/kawa, run a forced recognition program.
イシカワ
強制認識プログラムを流せ
lsh/kawa, run a forced recognition program.
Roger.
（イシカワ）了解
Aborz' the operation. Throw down
your guns and surrender
（男性）作戦中止
Aborz' the operation. Throw down
your guns and surrender
銃を捨てて投降しろ
Aborz' the operation. Throw down
your guns and surrender
（ゲリラ２）えっ…
（ゲリラ３）んん…
Repeat." Abort the operation and surrender.
（男性）繰り返す 作戦中止
投降しろ
Huh?
Aw, no shootout?
ドンパチなしかよ
I captured one!
（ロジコマ）捕まえましたー
おっ お前 結構 役に立つな
Hey, you're pretty useful!
（ロジコマ）エヘヘッ
最後の１人を捕らえた
We got the last one.
（素子）よし 全員 公安に引き渡せ
Good. Hand them all over to Public Security.
A virus alert?
（素子）感染警告？
It's the man you captured!
（バトー）お前が捕まえた男だ！
This pain...
この痛み…
The ghost lock released?
ゴーストロックが解けた？
（バトー）少佐！？
Ma/or?
くそ！
Shit'. Sa/'to/
（バトー）サイトー！
（サイトー）ああっ
（素子）殺すな！
（サイトー）うぐ…
Don '1' k/// him!
くうっ… あ！
No more of that!
そこまでだ
（サイトー）くそっ…
Damn, it feels gross having someone
infiltrate my Ghost-e I/en the Major.
いくら少佐でも―
Damn, it feels gross having someone
infiltrate my Ghost-e I/en the Major.
ゴーストに侵入されるのは
気分が悪いぜ
Damn, it feels gross having someone
infiltrate my Ghost-e I/en the Major.
Truer words...
（バトー）まったくだ
Your fault for aiming for the head.
（素子）頭を狙うからだ
まだ引き渡すな
Don't hand them over yet. We'll take
them to a lockup with cyber facilities.
全員 電脳設備のある留置所へ
連れていく
Don't hand them over yet. We'll take
them to a lockup with cyber facilities.
You telling me to play interrogation partner?
尋問につきあえってのか？
（素子）偽りの記憶に用はないわ
I'm not interested in fake memories.
記憶？
Memories?
I'm interested in their contaminated Ghosts.
（素子）こいつらの
汚染されたゴーストに用がある
I'm interested in their contaminated Ghosts.
Sorry I had to call you down here.
ご足労願って申し訳ありません
（サイード）
市民としての当然の義務ですから
It's my civic duty.
I understand you're in charge
of the dam. Let's see...
（トグサ）
あなたがダムの管理者ですね
I understand you're in charge
of the dam. Let's see...
えっと…
Dr. Zhinzhee Bekka Arr Thied.
ジンジ･ベッカ･アル･サイード博士
Please, call me Thied.
（サイード）
サイードと お呼びください
Please, call me Thied.
おっ 頑丈そうな秘書ですね
You've got quite the tough-looking secretary.
頼りになる部下です
He's very reliable.
あなたの故郷クザン共和国では
紛争が続いている
The conflicts continue in the Republic
of Kuzan, where you're from.
特に少数民族のカルディス人は―
I hear the Qhardi ethnic minority in particular
is still waging a war of independence.
独立戦争を
続けようとしているとか
I hear the Qhardi ethnic minority in particular
is still waging a war of independence.
It's a heartbreaking war.
痛ましい争いです
You're Qhardi, correct?
（トグサ）あなたも
カルディス人ですよね？
You're Qhardi, correct?
はい 大多数の同胞と同じく
平和的解決を望んでいます
Yes. Like the majority of my comrades,
I wish for a peaceful solution.
So, the explosion at the darn...
ダムの爆発ですが…
I'm told it was a valve malfunction.
（サイード）
バルブの異常と聞いています
I'm told it was a valve malfunction.
（トグサ）お宅の会社は
水の売買に関わっていますね
Your company sells water, right?
For what type of use?
使用目的は？
Your company sells water, right?
For what type of use?
（サイード）精密工業用水です
It's for precision machinery businesses.
That industry relies on 100% pure water.
純度100パーセントの水が
必要不可欠ですから
It's for precision machinery businesses.
That industry relies on 100% pure water.
Precision machinery...
Prosthetic manufacturing, for example?
（トグサ）
精密工業… 義体の製造とか？
Precision machinery...
Prosthetic manufacturing, for example?
（サイード）はい
Yes.
Chief...
（トグサ）部長…
You idiot!
（部長）バカ者が
The Trade Ministry got them
invited to set up a plant here!
（部長）産業省の肝いりで
誘致された企業だぞ
The Trade Ministry got them
invited to set up a plant here!
You want to make an enemy
of the local precinct, too?
管区の警官まで敵に回す気か？
You want to make an enemy
of the local precinct, too?
But...
（トグサ）そんな…
ちょっと それ 証拠品ですよ
Stop, that's evidence!
I'm very grateful to you for finding
the goods stolen from our warehouse.
（サイード）
我が社の倉庫から盗難された品を
発見してくださり―
I'm very grateful to you for finding
the goods stolen from our warehouse.
感謝しています
I'm very grateful to you for finding
the goods stolen from our warehouse.
（部長）お引き取りください
Please, take them with you.
え… 部長！
Chief!
よさんか
Back off!
A detective died, sir.
刑事が死んだんですよ？
You think I don't know that?
言われんでも分かっとる
You go to Nishinouchi and get me information.
お前は西ノ内で情報を集めてこい
Nishinouchi? What's there?
（トグサ）西ノ内って何です？
A bombing, apparently by Qhardi terrorists.
爆破テロだ
カルディス系の仕業らしい
A bombing, apparently by Qhardi terrorists.
いいか
この件は 上とよく相談して…
Now listen: You consult your superiors
before any moves on this case.
Terrorism?
（トグサ）テロ…
If the explosion was intentional,
and he wasn't a victim...
もし 爆破が意図的で
かつ 被害者でもなければ…
If the explosion was intentional,
and he wasn't a victim...
What?
（部長）何？
Yes, sir! I'm on it!
分かりました 行ってきます
Don't make any trouble!
余計なマネは するんじゃないぞ
They're a Qhardi weapons smuggling gang.
I met them on an undercover op.
（パズ）
カルディス系の武器密輸組織だ
They're a Qhardi weapons smuggling gang.
I met them on an undercover op.
潜入捜査で会ったことがある
They're a Qhardi weapons smuggling gang.
I met them on an undercover op.
Their goal is to send weapons
to their comrades back home.
連中の目的は
故郷の仲間に武器を送ることだ
Their goal is to send weapons
to their comrades back home.
この国を攻撃する理由がねえ
They've got no reason to attack this country.
（イシカワ）供述に混乱はなし
Their statements were crystal clear:
They're against the pricing agreement,
so they bombed the meeting site.
水の価格協定に反対して
会談場所を爆破した
They're against the pricing agreement,
so they bombed the meeting site.
それ自体 植え付けられた
偽の記憶だってのか？
Are you telling me those are planted memories?
全員が感染したほうに賭けるわ
I'm betting they're all infected.
それがゴーストロックと
干渉したことにもね
And that the virus interfered
with my ghost lock.
Well done. You subdued them brilliantly.
（荒巻(あらまき)）ご苦労 見事な制圧だった
そちらの通信規格を
私たちに合わせれば―
We could do it even more easily if you
adjusted your comm standards to ours.
もっと楽に制圧できるわよ
We could do it even more easily if you
adjusted your comm standards to ours.
I read your report.
報告は読んだ
ゴースト侵入ハック
A false memory virus that can infiltrate, hack,
洗脳全てを同時に行う
疑似記憶ウイルスか
and brainwash simultaneously?
And brainwash simultaneously?
It's a self-destructing Stuxnet-type.
（素子）自己消滅する
スタックスネット型よ
It's a self-destructing Stuxnet-type.
感染初期の症状以外
痕跡を残さないわ
Other than the symptoms at
its onset, it leaves no trace.
Electronic manipulation of
memory is incredibly difficult.
（荒巻）電子的な記憶操作は
難易度トリプルエーの技術だ
Electronic manipulation of
memory is incredibly difficult.
世界でも確かな成功例はない
No one in the world has
been confirmed successful.
And yet past incidents tell us a
maker and a broker clearly exist.
（素子）でも 過去の事件から―
And yet past incidents tell us a
maker and a broker clearly exist.
明らかに作成者とブローカーが
存在している
And yet past incidents tell us a
maker and a broker clearly exist.
（荒巻）そう
高度な電脳ウイルスを作った―
Yes. Somewhere out there is
the super-wizard-class programmer
超ウィザード級プログラマー ―
Yes. Somewhere out there is
the super-wizard-class programmer
known as "Fire-Starter" who created
this high-level cyber-virus.
通称 ファイア･スターターが
どこかにいる
Known as "Fire-Starter" who created
this high-level cyber-virus.
But until now, no organization in
the world had uncovered his identity.
だが 世界のどの機関も
正体をつかめずにいた
But until now, no organization in
the world had uncovered his identity.
つかめたの？
Did you?
（荒巻）片鱗をな
A clue, anyway.
これは？
What's this?
All the terrorists had the same tattoo.
（荒巻）実行犯全員に同じ入れ墨
It's a symbol used by Scylla, the hero
who once led the Qhardi Separatist Army.
かつて カルディス独立軍を
率いた英雄―
It's a symbol used by Scylla, the hero
who once led the Qhardi Separatist Army.
スクラサスが用いたシンボルだ
It's a symbol used by Scylla, the hero
who once led the Qhardi Separatist Army.
（バトー）聞いたことがある
電子戦の手だれだってウワサだ
I've heard of him. Word is he's
a master of cyber warfare.
そいつがファイア･スターター？
Is he Fire-Starter?
（素子）ありえない
戦争中に死んだはずよ
No way. He died during the war.
（荒巻）その真偽を確かめてもらう
You're going to find out whether that's true.
９課のデーターベースに
制限付きでアクセスを許可する
I'll authorize limited access
to Section 9's database.
Read the details there.
詳細は そちらで参照しろ
（素子）それだけ？
That's all?
You're complaining?
不服か？
I gave you all the Logicomas I have,
plus our weapons and permission to use them.
ロジコマをあるだけ提供した
I gave you all the Logicomas I have,
plus our weapons and permission to use them.
備品の銃器と その使用許可もな
I gave you all the Logicomas I have,
plus our weapons and permission to use them.
Any lists I make are meaningless
if the organization can't act.
私がリストを作っても―
Any lists I make are meaningless
if the organization can't act.
組織が活用できないんじゃ
意味がないわ
Any lists I make are meaningless
if the organization can't act.
（荒巻）どうしろと？
And?
I want special authority
and an approved budget.
（素子）特務権限と予算の承認
I want special authority
and an approved budget.
ついでに そっちの
ぜい弱な通信ラインから―
And make your flimsy comm lines backward
compatible with ours while you're at it.
私たちのラインに
上位互換してちょうだい
And make your flimsy comm lines backward
compatible with ours while you're at it.
（デスクをたたく音）
（荒巻）いいかげんにせんか！
Enough! Your team isn't regulation size,
and I'm graciously turning a blind eye!
規定の人数に満たんことに
目をつむってやっとるんだぞ
Enough! Your team isn't regulation size,
and I'm graciously turning a blind eye!
完璧な規格で統一された部隊よ
増員は必要ないわ
This unit is standardized to the perfect specs.
We don't need more people.
Then the whole unit will go down
the second you get hacked.
（荒巻）なら お前が
ハッキングされた時点で全滅だ
Then the whole unit will go down
the second you get hacked.
あの実行犯のようにな
Just like those terrorists did.
Your "perfect specs" don't merit my trust.
完璧な規格など信用に値せん
If you want authority and a budget,
get at least one more member
予算と権限が欲しいなら
最低あと１人加え―
If you want authority and a budget,
get at least one more member
and accept cooperation from
someone with different specs.
連携すべき相手と
異なる規格を受け入れろ
And accept cooperation from
someone with different specs.
If they won't give us money, we're stuck
in this garbage dump for a while.
（バトー）予算が下りねえなら―
If they won't give us money, we're stuck
in this garbage dump for a while.
まだ このガラクタ置き場と
オサラバできねえわけだ
If they won't give us money, we're stuck
in this garbage dump for a while.
I'm just glad we've got a lab to use.
（イシカワ）ラボが使えるだけ
ありがてえぜ
I'm just glad we've got a lab to use.
Yeah, high prosthetic performance
takes superior maintenance...
（パズ）結局
義体の性能を支えるのは―
Yeah, high prosthetic performance
takes superior maintenance...
優秀なメンテナンスだからな
Yeah, high prosthetic performance
takes superior maintenance...
We'll have to pay for upgrades
out of pocket. Costs a lot, though.
（ボーマ）バージョンアップは
自前でやるしかないな
We'll have to pay for upgrades
out of pocket. Costs a lot, though.
金は かかるが
Training ground instructors
make pretty good money.
（バトー）訓練所の教官は
いい金になるぜ
Training ground instructors
make pretty good money.
Top-quality maintenance facilities,
authority-we'll get it all.
高度なメンテナンス設備 権限
Top-quality maintenance facilities,
authority-we'll get it all.
全て手に入れる
Top-quality maintenance facilities,
authority-we'll get it all.
Stop wasting time bitching and solve our case!
ぼやく暇で事件をもぎ取れ
His nationality's unknown.
（イシカワ）国籍不明
He uses multiple bodies to conceal his identity,
複数の義体を使って―
正体を隠すことから付いた異名が
“スクラサス”
He uses multiple bodies to conceal his identity,
earning the name Skulla, aka Scylla.
Earning the name Skulla, aka Scylla.
別名 スキュラ
That's the name of a monster
from Greek mythology.
ギリシャ神話に出てくる
怪物の名前だ
That's the name of a monster
from Greek mythology.
A pro at warfare who led
a separatist army, and whiz hacker...
独立軍を指導した戦闘のプロで
凄腕のハッカー
A pro at warfare who led
a separatist army, and whiz hacker...
得意技がトンネル作戦とはな
Huh, his specialty is tunnel ops.
トンネルって？
"Tunnel ops"?
That's when you bomb someplace's lifelines
（イシカワ）
爆弾でライフラインを攻撃し―
and then infiltrate them
electronically during their restoration.
復旧する過程で
電子的に侵入するんだ
And then infiltrate them
electronically during their restoration.
最終的には攻撃対象の本丸に
破壊的な電子戦を仕掛ける
Ultimately you wage a destructive
cyber-attack from inside their defenses.
（ボーマ）
独立を阻止しようとしたほうは―
The forces who tried to prevent
independence took a major hit instead.
逆に大打撃を受けた
The forces who tried to prevent
independence took a major hit instead.
But Kuzan joined forces with advanced nations
だが クザン共和国が
周辺諸国をけん制するため―
But Kuzan joined forces with advanced nations
to manipulate the Qhardis in
order to contain its neighbors.
先進諸国と組んで操ったんだ
To manipulate the Qhardis in
order to contain its neighbors.
It was a throwaway war of independence,
and this country was especially involved.
特に この国が関与した
使い捨ての独立戦争さ
It was a throwaway war of independence,
and this country was especially involved.
No one recognized the Qhardis'
independence after the war,
戦後 カルディスの独立は
承認されず―
No one recognized the Qhardis'
independence after the war,
and the guerillas were
disbanded and slaughtered.
ゲリラは解体 皆殺しだ
And the guerillas were
disbanded and slaughtered.
But their dead leader was actually alive,
死んだ指導者が実は生きていて
世界の研究機関を出し抜き―
But their dead leader was actually alive,
and he developed a special virus ahead
of all the world's research institutions,
特殊なウイルスを開発
and he developed a special virus ahead
of all the world's research institutions,
then changed his name to
Fire-Starter and began his revenge...
名をファイア･スターターに変え
復讐を始めた…
then changed his name to
Fire-Starter and began his revenge...
I follow the logic, but is it really possible?
理屈は分かるが 可能なのか？
In a conflict zone, you can do all
the human experimentation you want.
紛争地域じゃ―
In a conflict zone, you can do all
the human experimentation you want.
電脳ウイルスの人体実験を
やりたい放題だ
In a conflict zone, you can do all
the human experimentation you want.
不思議は ねえなぁ
It's no wonder, really.
Scylla is dead.
（素子）
スクラサスは死んだはずよ
Scylla is dead.
A successor of his, then?
なら 後継者か？
何であれ
商品の性能も知らずに売る―
Either way, the broker isn't peddling
it without knowing what it does.
ブローカーじゃない
Either way, the broker isn't peddling
it without knowing what it does.
So he wanted to use those guerillas
to repeat his old tunnel operation here?
ゲリラを操って―
So he wanted to use those guerillas
to repeat his old tunnel operation here?
当時のトンネル作戦を
この国で再現する気だってのか？
So he wanted to use those guerillas
to repeat his old tunnel operation here?
It bothers me that no one
was carrying a detonator.
（素子）誰も爆弾の起爆装置を
持っていなかったのが気になる
It bothers me that no one
was carrying a detonator.
Borma, check out the crime scene.
ボーマ 現場を調べろ
Roger.
了解
Paz, you and Saito pay the gang a visit.
I want to know who trained them.
（素子）パズ
サイトーと組織を当たれ
Paz, you and Saito pay the gang a visit.
I want to know who trained them.
誰が連中を訓練したか知りたい
Paz, you and Saito pay the gang a visit.
I want to know who trained them.
Batou and lshikawa, you look into
the possibility of a tunnel op.
バトーとイシカワは
トンネル作戦の可能性を当たれ
Batou and lshikawa, you look into
the possibility of a tunnel op.
Do you plan to dive into
the guerillas' cyberbrains
お前は あのゲリラの電脳に潜って
ウイルスを探す気か？
Do you plan to dive into
the guerillas' cyberbrains
looking for the virus?
I'll get a tune-up on my body first.
（素子）その前に
義体をメンテするわ
I'll get a tune-up on my body first.
A tune-Up?
（イシカワ）メンテ？
It's her boyfriend.
He's an ex-military prosthetics tech.
彼氏だよ
元軍属の義体技師
It's her boyfriend.
He's an ex-military prosthetics tech.
No, isn't he a Navy sailor?
（ボーマ）海軍の船乗りだろ？
That was the last one.
そりゃ 前の男
They fought on a date,
デート中にケンカして
少佐に尻を蹴られて入院
and she kicked his ass hard enough
to put him in the hospital.
And she kicked his ass hard enough
What about that rich one
from the Cyberbrain Bureau?
電脳局の高給取りは？
He didn't last two weeks.
ありゃ ２週間 もたなかったな
So this is the sixth in six months?
She's got a sickness.
半年で６人目か 病気だな
So this is the sixth in six months?
She's got a sickness.
No, it's instinct. I never sleep
with the same woman twice either.
本能さ
俺も同じ女は二度と抱かない
No, it's instinct. I never sleep
with the same woman twice either.
Because you always end up a hostage
or a target for revenge?
人質や報復の対象にされるからか？
Because you always end up a hostage
or a target for revenge?
No, because it's my policy.
（パズ）いや そういう主義だ
（イシカワ）
相手の情報くらい押さえとけ
At least do background checks on them!
What if one of them's a trap?
ワナだったらどうする？
It's better than hearing, "I want a family".
（パズ）“家庭を持ちたい”って
言われるよりいい
It's better than hearing, "I want a family".
Yeah, after all, you could die at any time.
（バトー）どうせ
いつ死んでもいい身だしな
Yeah, after all, you could die at any time.
This is no job for a family man.
（ボーマ）
家庭を持つには不向きな仕事だ
This is no job for a family man.
（荒巻）亡くなった刑事の銃は
発見されずか…
So the late detective's gun wasn't found?
If Detective Mizuki had fired his weapon,
水城刑事が銃を使用していれば―
it would prove this was a crime,
and not an accident.
事故ではなく
事件だった証拠になります
It would prove this was a crime,
and not an accident.
You think someone wanted
it to look like an accident?
事故に見せかけたい
誰かがいたと？
You think someone wanted
it to look like an accident?
The cause of death was drowning,
but he lost a lot of blood antemortem,
死因は溺死ですが
生存中に大量の出血―
The cause of death was drowning,
but he lost a lot of blood antemortem,
and some of his bones are missing.
骨の一部が欠けて
体外に消えてます
And some of his bones are missing.
So the body's too damaged to tell,
but he may have been shot.
（荒巻）遺体の損傷が激しく
はっきりせんが―
So the body's too damaged to tell,
but he may have been shot.
撃たれた可能性がある か…
So the body's too damaged to tell,
but he may have been shot.
Detective Mizuki was
investigating weapons smuggling.
（トグサ）水城刑事は
武器密輸を追っていました
Detective Mizuki was
investigating weapons smuggling.
His most recent meeting was
with a Qhardi organization.
直近の相手は
カルディス系の組織です
His most recent meeting was
with a Qhardi organization.
I suspect he was killed because he found proof.
証拠をつかんだせいで
殺されたのでは… と
I suspect he was killed because he found proof.
You feel the dam explosion was intentional,
set up to bury evidence?
ダム爆破は意図的であり
目的は証拠を隠滅するためか
You feel the dam explosion was intentional,
set up to bury evidence?
You've got a great imagination.
空想がたくましいな
You're turning me down, sir?
ご協力いただけませんか
No, I like it. I'll allow you to investigate.
（荒巻）いや 面白い
捜査を許可する
No, I like it. I'll allow you to investigate.
Try to find a connection between the incidents.
そちらの件とのつながりを
見つけてみろ
Try to find a connection between the incidents.
１人で？
All alone?
（荒巻）不服か？
You're complaining?
I appreciate it, sir!
感謝します
Humans can never perfectly
reproduce movements.
（ホセ）人間が完全に
同じ動きをすることはありえない
Humans can never perfectly
reproduce movements.
A slight slope, our distance from our target,
a few milligrams' weight difference...
わずかな傾き 対象との距離―
A slight slope, our distance from our target,
a few milligrams' weight difference...
ミリグラム単位の重さ―
A slight slope, our distance from our target,
a few milligrams' weight difference...
The brain calculates all these things
to create yet-unknown movements.
そうしたものを計算しながら
脳は未知の動きを創造し続ける
The brain calculates all these things
to create yet-unknown movements.
（ホセ）
君の脳は誰よりも独創的で―
You have the most original brain I know of,
and you understand the beauty
of uniform standards.
統一された規格の美しさを
理解している
And you understand the beauty
of uniform standards.
You're exaggerating.
大げさね
There's nothing wrong with you.
異常はないよ
It still hurts?
まだ痛い？
アハハ… 右足 動かしてみて
Try moving your right leg.
Lovely.
きれいだ
What's "lovely"?
どこが？
Your leg.
足
イテッ…
The pain is gone now.
痛みは消えたわ
請求書を送って
The pain is gone now.
Send me a bill.
I'll give you a discount.
In return, don't forget our promise.
（ホセ）安くしとく
代わりに約束を忘れるな
I'll give you a discount.
In return, don't forget our promise.
You're a strange man.
（素子）あなた 変わってるわ
Not as strange as you.
（ホセ）君ほどじゃない
Hey, you. You're blocking my scan.
（ボーマ）おい
スキャニングの邪魔だぞ
Hey, you. You're blocking my scan.
Oh, sorry.
ああ すまない
What good are your natural
eyes in the cyber age?
（ボーマ）今どき生身の目で
何しようってんだ？
What good are your natural
eyes in the cyber age?
It's not normally this hard to find the epicenter.
（トグサ）爆発地点が
異様に分かりづらいな
It's not normally this hard to find the epicenter.
You know a lot about the combustion process?
（ボーマ）
燃焼プロセスの知識があるのか？
You know a lot about the combustion process?
I learned the basics overseas during the war.
（トグサ）戦中に外地で
マニュアルを習った
I learned the basics overseas during the war.
I see.
（ボーマ）あっ そう
Are you a full cyborg?
（トグサ）あんた 全身義体か？
Yeah, pretty close.
ああ ほぼな
I'm no expert, but unless you
get a specialized skeleton,
俺には
よく分からないんだが―
I'm no expert, but unless you
get a specialized skeleton,
特殊な骨格じゃないかぎり
基本は人体と同じだろ
aren't the basics the same as a human body's?
Aren't the basics the same as a human body's?
But his hands stayed open after he burned...
なのに 焼けても
手を開いたままなのか？
But his hands stayed open after he burned...
What?
何？
When a natural human burns to death,
生身の人間が焼け死ぬと―
his muscles contract, so he forms
fists and he bends forward.
筋肉の収縮で拳を握って
前屈みになる―
His muscles contract, so he forms
fists and he bends forward.
The fetal position, or,
you know, the boxer's pose.
胎児の姿勢とか
ボクサー姿勢ってやつ
The fetal position, or,
you know, the boxer's pose.
熱硬直か… それがどうした？
Heat rigor? Well, what about it?
This guard's corpse is standing
up straight, hands open.
発見された警備員の死体―
This guard's corpse is standing
up straight, hands open.
突っ立ったまま
両手を開いて死んでいる
This guard's corpse is standing
up straight, hands open.
Must be some property of
his prosthetics, or of the bomb.
義体か爆弾
どちらかの性質だろう
Must be some property of
his prosthetics, or of the bomb.
Prosthetics?
義体…
Hello?
Oh, a checkup?
ああ 検査か
Two weeks?
２週間後？
Got it. No, I'm working right now, sorry.
分かった
いや 仕事中なんだ すまない
Got it. No, I'm working right now, sorry.
検査？
"Checkup"?
Sorry to bother you.
邪魔したな
C-4 and dynamite, glycerin,
and chemical fertilizer...
（パズ）Ｃ４にダイナマイト
C-4 and dynamite, glycerin,
and chemical fertilizer...
グリセリンに化学肥料
It's a hideout straight out of a book.
いかにもなアジトだな
Definitely a bomb maniac vibe...
but I've got no clue what they actually used.
爆弾マニアって感じだが
Definitely a bomb maniac vibe...
but I've got no clue what they actually used.
実際 何を使用したか
さっぱり分からん
Definitely a bomb maniac vibe...
but I've got no clue what they actually used.
Orders coming down their line!
（イシカワ）
連中のラインに指示だ！
Orders coming down their line!
Someone calling himself Scylla just
ordered some "Second Army" into action.
（イシカワ）スクラサスの名で
第２群とやらへ実働命令！
Someone calling himself Scylla just
ordered some "Second Army" into action.
Damn bastards! Public Security's
moves are being leaked!
くそったれが
公安の動きが漏れてやがる
Damn bastards! Public Security's
moves are being leaked!
The Waterworks Bureau's server blew,
and took out' the who/e floor.
（素子）水道管理局のサーバーが
フロアごと吹っ飛んだ
The Waterworks Bureau's server blew,
and took out' the who/e floor.
What did they use?
何を使った？
The acce/eram' at the N/sh/nouch/ crime scene
（ボーマ）西ノ内の現場だが―
is spread all the way to
the ceiling, even the ducts.
燃焼促進が
天井やダクトにまで広がってる
Is spread all the way to
the ceiling, even the ducts.
We're talking omnidirectional b/asz'.
The air itself blew up.
全方位への爆風
We're talking omnidirectional b/asz'.
The air itself blew up.
つまり 空間自体が爆発した
We're talking omnidirectional b/asz'.
The air itself blew up.
A fuel-air explosive?
（バトー）気化爆弾か？
Then this is a dummy hideout. They've got
a more advanced bomb lab somewhere.
なら ここはダミーだ
Then this is a dummy hideout. They've got
a more advanced bomb lab somewhere.
どこかに もっと高度な爆弾の
製造場所がある
Then this is a dummy hideout. They've got
a more advanced bomb lab somewhere.
ん？ フンッ
Damn guerilla hero is issuing a challenge.
ゲリラの英雄が挑戦してやがる
The Waterworks Bureau is starting repairs-
Odds are the hacker's already in!
（イシカワ）
水道局が復旧を開始
The Waterworks Bureau is starting repairs-
Odds are the hacker's already in!
既にハッカーが潜り込んだ
可能性大だ
The Waterworks Bureau is starting repairs-
Odds are the hacker's already in!
Figure out' their next' target.
（素子）
次のターゲットを割り出せ
Don '1' let' them dig any more funnels-
これ以上
トンネルを掘らせるな
Don '1' let' them dig any more funnels-
ちいっ…
I appreciate your cooperation.
（トグサ）ご協力 感謝します
I'm used to police questioning.
（ホセ）警察の聴取には慣れてます
There've been a lot of
prosthetics thefts recently.
近頃は義体の盗難も多いですし
There've been a lot of
prosthetics thefts recently.
"Mermaid's Legs", eh?
マーメイド… 人魚の脚ですか
Not a very artistic name,
but it's easy to understand.
（ホセ）芸のない名前ですが
分かりやすいでしょ？
Not a very artistic name,
but it's easy to understand.
My female customers quite like it.
女性客には評判がいいんです
（トグサ）
こちらの脚に見覚えは？
Do you recognize these legs?
They appear to be the mass-production model.
（ホセ）量産型のようですね
タグを見てください
Look at the tag.
"Ariel".
“Ariel(エアリアル)”
I've asked around, and there's
no such model on the market.
調べましたが そういう製品は
出回ってないそうです
I've asked around, and there's
no such model on the market.
I don't carry it, either. It must be
a licensed designer's brand name.
うちも扱ってません
設計士が付けたブランドでしょう
I don't carry it, either. It must be
a licensed designer's brand name.
Designers use
the mass-production model as a base
量産型をベースに 客の要望で
斬新な形に加工するんです
Designers use
the mass-production model as a base
and then innovate to
meet customer demands.
And then innovate to
Any ideas?
心当たりは？
フッ…
うちのリストを お渡しします
I'll give you my list. One moment, please.
少々 お待ちください
Thank you.
助かります
フゥ…
Cops love lists. He'll be conveniently
absorbed in it for a while.
（ホセ）警察はリスト好きだ
Cops love lists. He'll be conveniently
absorbed in it for a while.
しばらく夢中になってくれる
Public Security took our dummy safe house.
（サイード）
公安がダミーハウスを押さえたぞ
Public Security took our dummy safe house.
Are the comm lines here safe, Colonel Hozumi?
ここの回線は大丈夫なのか？
ホヅミ大佐
Are the comm lines here safe, Colonel Hozumi?
Don't worry. It's one of
lntelligence's independent lines.
（ホヅミ）
情報部の独立ラインだ 安心しろ
Don't worry. It's one of
lntelligence's independent lines.
Why haven't you killed that detective?
あの刑事 なぜ始末しない？
He's an odd duck, but he doesn't
have any powerful backers.
妙な刑事だが
有力なバックはいない
He's an odd duck, but he doesn't
have any powerful backers.
The real issue is that Ariel's been leaked.
問題はエアリアルの流出だ
We retrieved the sample before it was
analyzed, and the factory is taken care of.
（サイード）分析される前に
回収した製造プラントも―
We retrieved the sample before it was
analyzed, and the factory is taken care of.
処分済みだ
I didn't expect you to panic and blow it up.
（ホヅミ）慌てて爆破するとはな
We're lucky Ariel was mounted in time.
You almost seriously hindered our plan.
エアリアルの実装が
間に合ったから よいものの―
We're lucky Ariel was mounted in time.
You almost seriously hindered our plan.
危うく 作戦に
支障を来すところだったぞ
We're lucky Ariel was mounted in time.
You almost seriously hindered our plan.
エアリアルは カルディスへ
爆薬を密輸する手段だ
Ariel is a way to smuggle explosives to
the Qhardis! It's not for suicide bombers!
自爆テロじゃない！
Ariel is a way to smuggle explosives to
the Qhardis! It's not for suicide bombers!
Circumstances have changed.
（ホヅミ）情勢の変化だ
If previous overseas weapons
development becomes domestic,
従来の兵器国外開発が
国内へ移行すれば―
If previous overseas weapons
development becomes domestic,
distribution channels will vanish.
流通ルートが消える
Distribution channels will vanish.
The Qhardi soldiers are just sacrificial pawns?
（ホセ）
カルディスの兵士は使い捨てか？
The Qhardi soldiers are just sacrificial pawns?
We're upgrading. Fire-Starter can
create all the soldiers we want.
（ホヅミ）バージョンアップだ
We're upgrading. Fire-Starter can
create all the soldiers we want.
ファイア･スターターなら
いくらでも兵士を生み出せる
We're upgrading. Fire-Starter can
create all the soldiers we want.
Get the unit that was arrested released.
（ホセ）
逮捕された部隊を釈放させろ
Get the unit that was arrested released.
それまでデータは渡せない
I won't give you the data until then.
They aren't even your compatriots.
お前の同胞ではないのに
スクラサスなら 彼らを見捨てない
Scylla would never abandon them.
Very well. There are three more usable Ariels.
（ホヅミ）よかろう
使用可能なエアリアルは あと３体
Very well. There are three more usable Ariels.
One of them is in your court.
うち１体は お前の範疇(はんちゅう)だぞ
It really has to be her?
本当に彼女なのか？
Have you developed feelings for her?
Activate the woman's Ariel.
（ホヅミ）情が移ったのか？
女のエアリアルを起動しろ
Have you developed feelings for her?
Activate the woman's Ariel.
Release our allies first. Understand?
（ホセ）
仲間の釈放が先だ いいな？
Release our allies first. Understand?
Ride with me.
（クルツ）乗ってくれ
You haven't told anyone that
you and I killed Scylla, I trust?
私とお前で
スクラサスを葬ったことは―
You haven't told anyone that
you and I killed Scylla, I trust?
しゃべっていないな？
No.
That op is a stain on both our records.
（クルツ）
あれは お互いの汚点となる作戦だ
That op is a stain on both our records.
It would be highly inconvenient
for it to come up again now.
今 蒸し返されるのは都合が悪い
It would be highly inconvenient
for it to come up again now.
I see you dived happily into the power
games as soon as you made LTC.
中佐に昇進して 早速
パワーゲームを楽しんでるわけね
I see you dived happily into the power
games as soon as you made LTC.
戦時ビジネスで 命を
金に換えてきた連中を一掃する―
They used the military-industrial
complex to profit from death.
I'll wipe them out, make domestic
weapons engineering big,
兵器開発を国内主体にし―
I'll wipe them out, make domestic
weapons engineering big,
国外カルテルとべったりの
売買ルートを消滅させる
and shut down their trade
routes to foreign cartels.
And shut down their trade
Lt. Col. Mamuro wanted that.
マムロ中佐が望んでいたことだ
お前のゲームに参加する気はない
I won't play your game.
Scylla is a game you can't quit.
She has to stay dead.
（クルツ）スクラサスは
降りることのできないゲームだ
Scylla is a game you can't quit.
She has to stay dead.
彼女は死んでなければならない
Scylla is a game you can't quit.
She has to stay dead.
You used this before.
お前が使った品だ
Bury it and whoever's using
Scylla's name-permanently this time.
スクラサスを名乗る者と共に
今度こそ葬れ
Bury it and whoever's using
Scylla's name-permanently this time.
Or else the brass will bury you,
and that op with you.
さもなくば 過去の作戦ごと
軍部が お前を葬る
Or else the brass will bury you,
and that op with you.
Becoming independent of
the system doesn't make you free.
システムから独立したところで
自由には なれん
Becoming independent of
the system doesn't make you free.
You're like last century's programmers,
who expected too much from the birth of the Net.
ネットの誕生に過度な期待を抱いた
前世紀のプログラマーたちと同じだ
You're like last century's programmers,
who expected too much from the birth of the Net.
Even Section 9 is only letting you
have your own way to test you.
公安９課とて お前を独走させ
試しているだけさ
Even Section 9 is only letting you
have your own way to test you.
When they need to, they'll restrain
you with a Ghost infiltration key
いざとなれば
ゴースト侵入キーで拘束して―
When they need to, they'll restrain
you with a Ghost infiltration key
使い捨てにする
and dispose of you.
I have no intention of letting
anyone infiltrate my Ghost again.
二度と私のゴーストに
侵入させる気はないわ
I have no intention of letting
anyone infiltrate my Ghost again.
相手が誰であっても
No matter who they are.
（エマ）あの人が草薙(くさなぎ)素子
That woman is Motoko Kusanagi?
お前の先輩だ 勝てるか？
Yes, your senior. Can you win?
If you wish.
（エマ）あなたが望むなら
You really came?
本当に来たの？
I did promise.
約束だからな
I haven't prepared anything.
（素子）何も用意してないわ
I figured.
（ホセ）だと思ったよ
But first, we'll take care of this.
だが その前に
こっちからだな
But first, we'll take care of this.
I checked out the Qhardi gang, but there's
no trace of their tactical commander.
（パズ）
カルディス系の組織を追ったが―
I checked out the Qhardi gang, but there's
no trace of their tactical commander.
戦術を指導したやつは
影も形もない
I checked out the Qhardi gang, but there's
no trace of their tactical commander.
Ah, but I've got the rental server they used.
代わりに連中が使った
レンタルサーバーを押さえたぜ
Ah, but I've got the rental server they used.
Multiple invaders into a public facility...
公共施設への複数の侵入
相当 トンネルを
掘り進めてやがる
Bastards have made good
progress on their tunnels.
Do you know where they're going yet'?
（素子）
ゴール地点は まだ見えないか？
Do you know where they're going yet'?
It's someplace to do with
water and precision machinery.
（イシカワ）
水と精密機械に関わる場所だ
It's someplace to do with
water and precision machinery.
78 places in the city fit that description.
該当する施設は都市内に78箇所
Check them all.
（素子）しらみ潰しにしろ
Damn... I'd make easier money
being an Intelligence subcontractor.
ったく… 情報部の下請けのほうが
よっぽど楽に もうかるぜ
Damn... I'd make easier money
being an Intelligence subcontractor.
So, sf/I/ in your ”z'une-up”?
（バトー）
で？ お前は まだメンテ中か？
So, sf/I/ in your ”z'une-up”?
（素子）そうだ しばらく切るぞ
Yes. I'm dropping this connection for a While.
I can hear noise. Your coworkers are
in and out of your lobby nonstop, huh?
ノイズが聞こえる
I can hear noise. Your coworkers are
in and out of your lobby nonstop, huh?
君の電脳ロビーは
仕事相手がひっきりなしだな
I can hear noise. Your coworkers are
in and out of your lobby nonstop, huh?
I ran them all off.
みんな追い出したわ
You think I'll ever get to be in your lobby?
そのうち俺も
ロビーに入れるかな
You think I'll ever get to be in your lobby?
If you work with me.
私と仕事をしてくれるなら
If I said I needed one
more person, would you come?
もし あと１人必要だって言ったら
来てくれる？
If I said I needed one
more person, would you come?
君をいつでもメンテできるのは
魅力だが…
Tuning you up whenever I want
is an attractive proposition,
but I don't get involved with
the military or the police.
軍や警察には
関わらないと決めてる
But I don't get involved with
the military or the police.
Oh.
そう…
感覚素子の応急処置をした
微調整はラボでやろう
I did some first aid on
your sensory components.
Let's do the detail work in the lab.
The pain is gone. I'll do the rest myself.
痛みは消えたし
あとは自分でやるわ
The pain is gone. I'll do the rest myself.
Then let's get started.
なら始めよう
I remember when I first met you, you know.
（ホセ）君と出会ったときのことを
覚えてるよ
I remember when I first met you, you know.
All the other engineers said you were
the queen of customer complaints.
エンジニア仲間全員―
All the other engineers said you were
the queen of customer complaints.
君をとんでもないクレーマーだって
ウワサしてた
All the other engineers said you were
the queen of customer complaints.
Is that why they handed me
off to a freelancer like you?
それで フリーのあなたに回された
Is that why they handed me
off to a freelancer like you?
Nope. The truth is, I asked them to.
いや 実は回してもらった
What?
You couldn't decide whether you should
treat your body as a thing or a person-
（ホセ）君は迷っていた
You couldn't decide whether you should
treat your body as a thing or a person-
自分の体を物として扱うべきか
人として扱うべきか
You couldn't decide whether you should
treat your body as a thing or a person-
That made me interested in you.
そんな君に興味が湧いてね
At the facility I was in before,
以前いた施設では ベッドで寝て
シャワーを浴びたがるって―
they thought I was an oddball for wanting
to sleep in a bed and take showers.
They thought I was an oddball for wanting
珍しがられたわ
to sleep in a bed and take showers.
When I was prosthetized on
the battlefield, they told me,
俺も戦場で義体になったとき
言われた
When I was prosthetized on
the battlefield, they told me,
サイボーグに必要なのは
生活ではなく 設備だと
"A cyborg doesn't need everyday life;
he needs equipment."
That's why I switched to
prosthetics engineering.
それで 義体技師に転向した
That's why I switched to
prosthetics engineering.
I wanted to be a tech who'd
treat cyborgs like humans.
義体を人間として扱う技師に
なりたくて
I wanted to be a tech who'd
treat cyborgs like humans.
As a kid, they gave me everyday-living
training outside the facility.
（素子）子供のころ
施設の外で生活する訓練を受けたわ
As a kid, they gave me everyday-living
training outside the facility.
So /'d learn how to be more human-
人間らしさを学習するために
/ don't real/y remember it.
Everything was so bright...
あまり記憶がない
何もかも まぶしくて…
/ don't real/y remember it.
Everything was so bright...
予定より早く戻ったことを
覚えてる
I remember I came back ahead of schedule.
But... That day I decided
to make my body orthodox.
ただ… そのとき―
But... That day I decided
to make my body orthodox.
義体はオーソドックスにするって
決めたの
But... That day I decided
to make my body orthodox.
I wanted to look human.
人の形がいいって
Your prosthetic body isn't a thing.
It's your real body.
君の義体は物体じゃない
君の肉体だ
Your prosthetic body isn't a thing.
It's your real body.
It mustn't be treated as a thing...
not by anyone.
物として扱われては
いけないんだ 誰からも
It mustn't be treated as a thing...
not by anyone.
Not by me.
この俺からも
I do wish that were true.
そうだったらと思うわ
I'll show you proof.
（ホセ）証拠を見せよう
Proof?
証拠？
It's a surprise.
（ホセ）見てのお楽しみさ
We're missing the key piece." the bomb.
（ボーマ）
肝心の爆弾が分からん
We're missing the key piece." the bomb.
How did they get it into a heavily
guarded meeting place?
厳重に守られた会談場所に
どうやって放り込んだか
How did they get it into a heavily
guarded meeting place?
What about the perps?
実行犯は？
They say they're the ones who blew it up.
自分たちが爆破したと言ってる
Despite the fact that they
have no memory of the bomb.
爆弾の記憶そのものが
ないにもかかわらず
Despite the fact that they
have no memory of the bomb.
（パズ）連中はおとりで
恐らく爆弾とは無関係だ
They're fall guys. They probably
have nothing to do with the bomb.
We'll monitor all 78 locations until
we can narrow down their target.
（素子）
ターゲットが絞り込めるまで
78箇所 全て監視する
We'll monitor all 78 locations until
we can narrow down their target.
Are you serious?!
（バトー）マジかよ！？
Contact me if something happens.
何かあれば連絡しろ
You're wearing heels-
ヒールなんぞ履いて！
Should we assume the ex-military
prosthetics tech is joining the team?
そのうち元軍属の義体技師が
メンバーになるってか？
Should we assume the ex-military
prosthetics tech is joining the team?
Maybe that's actually for real.
意外にマジかもな？
これが見せたかったもの？
This is what you wanted to show me?
They're regular customers of mine.
俺のお得意さまたちさ
Their average age is 70.
平均年齢70歳
They're all full-body cyborgs...
（素子）みんな 全身義体…
The affluent elderly are at the core
of cyborg development these days.
（ホセ）
今のサイボーグ開発の主体は―
The affluent elderly are at the core
of cyborg development these days.
裕福な高齢者だ
Not soldiers.
兵士じゃない
義体による第二の人生と
豊かな生活を求める人たちだ
They want prosthetic bodies to give them
second lives, and fulfilling lifestyles.
More and more foods for cyborgs are
being developed to meet their needs, too.
義体用の食品も 彼らのニーズで
どんどん開発されている
More and more foods for cyborgs are
being developed to meet their needs, too.
Try it.
試してみて
It's good.
おいしい
Is it your first time allocating
memory to your sense of taste?
味覚にメモリーを回すのは初めて？
Is it your first time allocating
memory to your sense of taste?
The new bride is pregnant, by the way.
ちなみに
あの新婦は妊娠している
The new bride is pregnant, by the way.
Exciting, isn't it? A new world
of humans that don't distinguish
ワクワクするだろ？
Exciting, isn't it? A new world
of humans that don't distinguish
義体と肉体の区別のない
新しい人間の世界なんて
Exciting, isn't it? A new world
of humans that don't distinguish
between prosthetic and flesh.
Between prosthetic and flesh.
You really are strange.
あなた 本当に変わってるわ
（ホセ）
中には未来を拒む人もいる
Some people reject the future.
And some are left behind by it, too.
そして
未来に取り残される人たちも
Some people reject the future.
And some are left behind by it, too.
I want to bring the cyborg
future to the third world.
義体の未来を
第三国へもたらしたい
I want to bring the cyborg
future to the third world.
Will you come with me?
一緒に行かないか？
You should use your power freely, not work
under a bunch of master manipulators.
君は自由に力を使うべきだ
You should use your power freely, not work
under a bunch of master manipulators.
人を操ることにたけた
連中の下なんかではなく…
You should use your power freely, not work
under a bunch of master manipulators.
The war is over, you know.
（素子）戦争は終わったのよ
No, it's still going.
（ホセ）続いてるさ
The nations it grew inconvenient
for pulled out, that's all.
都合が悪くなった国が
一方的に やめただけで
The nations it grew inconvenient
for pulled out, that's all.
I have things to do in this country.
（素子）私は
この国でやることがあるわ
I have things to do in this country.
I see.
（ホセ）そうか
Do you have free time later?
（素子）このあと時間ある？
If we share a lobby, we can
meet whenever we want.
ロビーを共有すれば
いつでも会えるでしょ？
If we share a lobby, we can
meet whenever we want.
I might touch your Ghost.
（ホセ）君のゴーストに
触れるかもしれない
I might touch your Ghost.
I'll let down my barrier.
（素子）防壁を解くわ
- Are you sure?
- If you infiltrate me, I may fry your brain.
いいのか？
- Are you sure?
- If you infiltrate me, I may fry your brain.
侵入したら脳を焼くかも
- Are you sure?
- If you infiltrate me, I may fry your brain.
It might be worth it.
その価値は ありそうだ
This is your body.
（ホセ）これが君の体…
These are your hands.
（素子）これが あなたの手…
（ホセ）うう！
（ニグチ）ぐう…
Motoko, run!
逃げろ 素子！
（ニグチ）ぬぐー！
うりゃ！
Akira!
アキラ…
（ホセ）う…
Are you all right?
（素子）無事？
Yeah...
ハァ
I'm sorry. This is my fault.
（素子）
ごめんなさい 私のせいで…
I'm sorry. This is my fault.
（サイトー）ハァ… ああ…
My condolences.
ご愁傷さま
Paz is with Section 9 inspecting the scene.
パズが９課と現場検証中
Your attacker was a pro,
even if he did mess up.
相手はプロだな
しくじったけどよ
Your attacker was a pro,
even if he did mess up.
It's unclear whether this
was tied to the bombing,
事件との関連は不明だが―
but we'd normally give you
police protection at this point.
お前に警護をつけるのが
通常の対応だ
But we'd normally give you
police protection at this point.
I don't need it. How is he?
（素子）要らないわ あの人は？
聴取が終わりしだい 帰宅させる
We'll send him home as soon
as we're done questioning him.
I'll assign someone to him, so don't worry.
人員はつけるから心配するな
I see.
（素子）そう
The military authorities won't
give me any information on Scylla.
（荒巻）
軍部はスクラサスに関する情報を
出そうとせん
The military authorities won't
give me any information on Scylla.
What's your connection to him?
お前と どう関係している？
Call me whenever you need help.
助けが必要なときは
いつでも呼べ
Call me whenever you need help.
スクラサスの報復か
彼氏が 一般人なのが救いだな
Scylla's revenge, eh?
Good thing your boyfriend's a civilian.
We don't have to suspect a leak.
リークを疑う必要がない
Good thing your boyfriend's a civilian.
We don't have to suspect a leak.
（ボーマ）やられたぞ
They go! us.
３つ目 湾岸の資材管理所だ
Number Three-" a materials
control center on the coast.
（イシカワ）爆破の30秒前に
スクラサスの名で実行命令を傍受
/ picked up a go order in Soy/la's name
30 seconds before the explosion-
ラインごと消えた
Then the who/e line disappeared.
At this rate, there's no point in surveillance-
これじゃ 監視の意味がねえぜ
Then the who/e line disappeared.
At this rate, there's no point in surveillance-
Find a weapons engineer on their
customer list who's connected to this-
（素子）資材管理リストから―
Find a weapons engineer on their
customer list who's connected to this-
つながりのある兵器開発業者を
見つけろ
Find a weapons engineer on their
customer list who's connected to this-
Weapons engineer?
（イシカワ）兵器開発？
Get info from the first victims, too. Hurry up.
（素子）
最初の被害者からもだ 急げ
Get info from the first victims, too. Hurry up.
Find something. The virus,
the bombs, the tactical commander,
ウイルス 爆弾 戦術指導者
Find something. The virus,
the bombs, the tactical commander,
where the messages from ”Scy//a”
come from-l don '2' care what.
スクラサスを名乗る通信の出どころ
何でもいい
where the messages from ”Scy//a”
come from-l don '2' care what.
何かをつかめ
そろそろ話したらどうだ
How about you finally tell us
why you're so sure Scylla's dead?
なんで お前は
スクラサスの死を確信している？
How about you finally tell us
why you're so sure Scylla's dead?
（トグサ）失礼
Excuse me.
YOu!
お前…
I was told I could find Major Kusanagi here.
ここに草薙少佐がいるって
聞いたんだが
I was told I could find Major Kusanagi here.
What is it?
（素子）何だ？
（素子）用件を言え
State your business.
The list I got from him was a fake.
（トグサ）彼から渡されたリストは
まがい物でした
The list I got from him was a fake.
And a detective working
a weapons trafficking case
武器密売を追って
殺された刑事も―
And a detective working
a weapons trafficking case
was killed right after getting info from him.
彼から情報を得てのち
殺されてる
Was killed right after getting info from him.
Techs get blamed for
prosthetics-related incidents all the time.
よくあることね
Techs get blamed for
prosthetics-related incidents all the time.
義体を巡る事件の責任を
義体技師に押しつけるのは
Techs get blamed for
prosthetics-related incidents all the time.
And the manager of the dam
that exploded the other day...
（トグサ）先日 爆破があった
ダムの管理者ですが―
And the manager of the dam
that exploded the other day...
ボディーガードの整備も彼が
Hose outfitted her bodyguard, too.
So what?!
だから 何だ？
How did you feel, watching your
lover get attacked in front of you?
恋人が目の前で襲われて
どう感じましたか？
How did you feel, watching your
lover get attacked in front of you?
あなたは 犯人への怒りと
罪悪感を抱いている
You're angry at the perp,
and you feel guilty.
You think it was your fault he got attacked.
自分のせいで恋人が襲われたと…
He was the same way. Anger and guilt.
彼も あなたと同じだった
怒りと罪悪感だ
He was the same way. Anger and guilt.
彼は何かを隠してる
He's hiding something.
ダム 死んだ刑事 義体―
The dam, the dead detective,
the prosthetics, and even you, Major...
そして 少佐 あなたも
The dam, the dead detective,
the prosthetics, and even you, Major...
Everything links back to Akira Hose.
全て ホセ･アキラにつながる
You're just a cheap detective
snooping around with flesh eyes!
生身の目で
のぞき回るだけの刑事が！
You're just a cheap detective
snooping around with flesh eyes!
Never show your face here again!
二度と顔を見せるな！
（トグサ）ああ… イッテ～
Ouch.
You're an idiot, Colonel!
あんたはバカだ 大佐！
攻性防壁！
An attack barrier!
Keep calm.
（ホヅミ）うろたえるな
If the domestic faction takes
away your arms industry rights,
（ホセ）国内派に
兵器産業の利権を奪われれば―
If the domestic faction takes
away your arms industry rights,
you'll be killed by the cartels.
あんたはカルテルに殺される
Yet you're in a rush to kill
me off and steal my data?
だが 焦って俺を始末し
データを奪うだと？
Yet you're in a rush to kill
me off and steal my data?
So, you act like a heavyweight,
but you couldn't get my people released?
大物ぶっておいて
仲間を釈放できなかったのか？
So, you act like a heavyweight,
but you couldn't get my people released?
Where is the data?
（ホヅミ）データは どこにある？
Our deal is over.
I'm thankful for the info on her
取り引きは終わりだ
Our deal is over.
I'm thankful for the info on her
彼女の情報とスクラサスの復活には
感謝するがな
Our deal is over.
I'm thankful for the info on her
and for Scylla's revival,
but I'm leaving this country.
And for Scylla's revival,
俺は この国を出る
but I'm leaving this country.
あんたもそうしろ
You do the same.
（ホヅミ）必要ない
No need.
We've successfully packaged
the virus with cyberbrains.
（ホヅミ）我々はウイルスと電脳の
パッケージ化に成功した
We've successfully packaged
the virus with cyberbrains.
We'll use your cyberbrain for the final upgrade.
（ホヅミ）お前の電脳で
最後のバージョンアップを行う
We'll use your cyberbrain for the final upgrade.
Become Scylla, just like you wanted to.
望みどおり スクラサスになれ
両手を開いたまま死んだ… か
"His hands stayed open after he burned", eh?
It's just' like the call said.
（パズ）連絡どおりだ
Two Public Security officers killed,
and Akira Hose's whereabouts unknown-
公安員２名が殺され
ホセ･アキラは行方不明
Two Public Security officers killed,
and Akira Hose's whereabouts unknown-
The Major Wasn't the target?
（バトー）
狙われたのは少佐じゃない？
（ボーマ）
おい リストを見てくれ
Hey, look at' this list'.
It's only a guess, but / think the FAEs
were the prosthetic limbs themselves-
推測の域を出ないが…
It's only a guess, but / think the FAEs
were the prosthetic limbs themselves-
気化爆弾の正体は
義体の手足そのものだ
It's only a guess, but / think the FAEs
were the prosthetic limbs themselves-
ビルの爆発現場にも
全身義体の警備兵がいた
There was another full-cyborg guard
in that part of the building.
手足の管理記録に
同じ人間のサインがある
The limbs' admin records have
the same signature on them...
What are you doing?
（鑑識官）ちょっと何です…
（ゲリラ１）うっ！
Who is this man?!
この男は誰だ！
（ゲリラ１）うううう…
My attack barrier expands every second.
１秒ごとに進行する攻性防壁だ
If you don't want your brain fried, tell me!
脳を焼かれたくなければ言え！
（赤服）死んでしまうぞ！
He'll die!
He gave us power... He's the new Scylla!
（ゲリラ１）
お… 俺たちに力をくれた！
He gave us power... He's the new Scylla!
新しいスクラサスだ！
It was like magic. A battle-learning
program left to us by the dead Scylla...
まるで魔法だった
It was like magic. A battle-learning
program left to us by the dead Scylla...
死んだスクラサスが残した
戦闘学習プログラム
It was like magic. A battle-learning
program left to us by the dead Scylla...
He gave it to my cyberbrain,
along with the virus.
それをウイルスと一緒に
俺の電脳に流した
He gave it to my cyberbrain,
along with the virus.
I'd never been trained, but now
I can fight even your people!
訓練も受けてない俺が
お前たちと戦えるようになった
I'd never been trained, but now
I can fight even your people!
Give me a name.
（素子）名前を言え！
Akira Hose! He's Japanese, like you!
ホセ･アキラ
お前と同じ日本人だ！
Akira Hose! He's Japanese, like you!
Hose escaped. Any idea where?
ホセが逃げた 心当たりは？
Why ask me?
なんで俺に…
What are your eyes looking at right now?
（素子）
お前の目は今 何を見ている？
What are your eyes looking at right now?
Zhinzhee Bekka Arr Thied.
ジンジ･ベッカ･アル･サイード
She's boss of a Kuzan water company,
and most likely the weapons ring's sponsor.
クザン系水企業の親玉で
恐らくは―
She's boss of a Kuzan water company,
and most likely the weapons ring's sponsor.
武器密売グループのスポンサーです
She's boss of a Kuzan water company,
and most likely the weapons ring's sponsor.
So this is the tunnel exit!
（イシカワ）
これか！ トンネルの出口
So this is the tunnel exit!
A domestic weapons company-
Har/madara Hea vy Industries!
国内の兵器開発業者
ハリマダラ重工業
A domestic weapons company-
Har/madara Hea vy Industries!
The execs are touring Factory One with
the Sen/or Vice-Minister of Defense!
第一工場で
重役と防衛副大臣が視察中だ
The execs are touring Factory One with
the Sen/or Vice-Minister of Defense!
Recommend a barrier,
and give the data f0 Sect/on .9.
（素子）防壁を勧告
Recommend a barrier,
and give the data f0 Sect/on .9.
９課にデータを渡せ
Paz, Borma, Sa/fo, get over there.
パズ ボーマ サイトー
現地に行け
Paz, Borma, Sa/fo, get over there.
Call the bomb squad and a prosthetics tech.
（荒巻）
爆発物処理班と電脳技師を呼べ
Call the bomb squad and a prosthetics tech.
A destructive cyber-attack is more than likely.
破壊的な電子的攻撃の可能性大だ
What's the meaning of this, Chief Aramaki?
（北原(きたはら)）
どういうことです？ 荒巻部長
What's the meaning of this, Chief Aramaki?
Evacuate immediately.
（荒巻）今すぐ退避を
You and this facility are targets.
あなた方と この施設が
ターゲットです
You and this facility are targets.
Wh-What's going on?!
（警備兵）な… 何だ？ これ！
爆弾だ！ 逃げろ！
It's a bomb! Run!
しまった！
（サイトー）くっそー！
- Damn.
- Shit!
（サイトー）
パズ ボーマ こっちだ！
Paz, Borma! This way!
Help me! Help me!
（警備兵）助けて！ 助けて！
（サイトー）
くそっ 炎で声が出ねえ
Crap, the fire's closing up my throat.
（ボーマ）
こっちもだ ヤバかったな
Mine I00. That was close.
Vice-Minister, are you all right?
（荒巻）副大臣 ご無事で
（北原）うむ… 大丈夫だ
I'm fine.
- Log/coma.
- Yes, sir!
（ボーマ）ロジコマ
- Log/coma.
- Yes, sir!
（ロジコマ）はーい！
（役員）我が社の商品が…
That's one of our products...!
（荒巻）奥へ！
Away from the windows!
ホヅミ大佐の情報は以上だ
That's all the info on Colonel Hozumi.
結構
That's fine. We get a card,
and you get a grace period.
我々はカードを得て
そちらは猶予を得る
That's fine. We get a card,
and you get a grace period.
教えてくれ
彼女とスクラサスの関係を
Please tell me what she has to do with Scylla!
あいつから聞け
Find out from her.
Your contaminated brain is intriguing,
汚染されたお前の電脳は興味深いが
感染する前に切断させてもらう
Find out from her.
Your contaminated brain is intriguing,
but I'm cutting our connection
before the infection spreads.
But I'm cutting our connection
Goodbye.
さよなら
（ホセ）汚染か…
Contaminated, eh?
I'm being bankrupted by a special
tax on foreign companies?!
（サイード）
外国企業への特殊課税で倒産だと…
I'm being bankrupted by a special
tax on foreign companies?!
こんなことが許されるのか？
How can this be allowed?!
（ホセ）
国内派の連中がやりそうなことだ
It's the kind of thing
the domestic faction would do.
どうする気だ？
大佐を殺すのか？
What do you plan to do? Kill the colonel?
She's all washed up. And so are you and I.
やつは終わりだ
俺も あんたも
She's all washed up. And so are you and I.
逃げて 国内派に服従しろ
Escape, and obey the domestic faction.
あんたの会社は
この国の税金という名目で潰される
Your company will be crushed under
the pretext of this nation's taxes.
このままじゃ
カルテルに殺されるぞ
You'll be killed by the cartels
if you don't do something.
（バトー）少佐 大丈夫か？
You okay, Major?
（素子）問題ない
No prob/ems. You go with that
detective and subdue the guards.
お前は刑事と一緒に
警備を押さえろ
No prob/ems. You go with that
detective and subdue the guards.
スクラサスは… 私がやる
/'// take care of Say/la.
Jeez, so stubborn. That's a scary lady.
意地張って まあ…
おっかない
Jeez, so stubborn. That's a scary lady.
What? A Mateba, in this day and age?
何だ？
今どき まだマテバかよ？
悪いかよ
What's wrong with that?!
It's the gun I trust the most.
いちばん信用できるんだ
What's wrong with that?!
It's the gun I trust the most.
フンッ
Blood traces. Someone was shot.
血の跡だ
誰かが撃たれたな
Blood traces. Someone was shot.
弾丸…
A bullet...
Ariel. So these are the prosthetic bombs.
エアリアル… これが義体爆弾か
ていっ うおお！
（バトー）
今のは てめえじゃねえな
That wasn't you just now.
Who the hell infiltrated my vision?!
誰が俺の視界に侵入しやがった？
That wasn't you just now.
Who the hell infiltrated my vision?!
Don't move!
動くな！
（ホセ）スクラサスは―
In that quagmire of a war, Scylla was
the only soldier I could empathize with.
あの泥沼の戦争で
唯一 俺が共感できる兵士だった
In that quagmire of a war, Scylla was
the only soldier I could empathize with.
なぜ 殺されたのか
ずっと君に聞きたかった
I've always wanted to ask
you why he was killed.
You didn't kill Scylla. I finally realized that.
君はスクラサスを殺していない
それが やっと分かった
You didn't kill Scylla. I finally realized that.
Go home. Or your Ariel will activate.
帰れ このままでは
君のエアリアルが起動する
Go home. Or your Ariel will activate.
Even / can't stop it.
（ホセ）俺にも止められない
（ボディーガード）ぐうう
What's going on here? That bastard
infiltrated my vision exact/y the way you do./
（バトー）どうなってる？
What's going on here? That bastard
infiltrated my vision exact/y the way you do./
お前そっくりの方法で
俺の視覚に侵入しやがったぞ
What's going on here? That bastard
infiltrated my vision exact/y the way you do./
くそったれ！
返事をしろ 少佐！
Answer me, Major!
軍は何をしている？
このままでは全滅するぞ！
What's taking the Army so long?!
We'll all die like this!
（イシカワ）機体を掌握された
It's been seized.
パッケージ化された何かを
断たないかぎり止まらん
It won '1' stop until we shut down
whatever it's packaged with-
Transplanted memories.
（素子）移植された記憶
（イシカワ）何？
What?
The packaged cyberbra/ns are the virus's hosts-
（素子）パッケージ化された電脳が
ウイルスのホスト
The packaged cyberbra/ns are the virus's hosts-
カルディスで 私がばらまいた
戦術プログラムを記憶化した―
They converted the faof/oa/ program
/ set loose in Ohard/sfan to memory.
私のコピー
My 00,01'-
What the hell are you saying?!
何を言ってやがる？
素子…
Motoko.
（ホセ）
結局 君を追い 君に捕らえられた
I came after you, but in the end,
you captured me.
It was my cyberbrain that was packaged.
パッケージ化されたのは
俺の電脳だ
It was my cyberbrain that was packaged.
引き金を引けば
君も仲間も助かる
If you pull the trigger,
you and your comrades will be saved.
君が恋をしたのは この世界だ
What you fell in love with was this world.
Just keep on going,
until the day you're betrayed.
いつか裏切られる日まで
歩み続ければいい
Just keep on going,
until the day you're betrayed.
スクラサス…
Scylla...
君に会えて よかった
I'm glad I met you.
（ロジコマ）はて？
What?
（パズ）止まった…
It stopped...
（バトー）皮肉だぜ
It's ironic.
せっかく大戦を
生き延びたってのに―
They manage to survive a world war,
then get stuck in an endless one,
みんな 終わらない戦争に
ハマったあげく―
They manage to survive a world war,
then get stuck in an endless one,
and finally end their own lives.
命にケリをつけやがる
And finally end their own lives.
それ以外
止める手段がないみたい
Apparently there's no other way they can stop.
（バトー）
お前も そうだったんだろ？
Weren't you the same?
スクラサスの正体は お前だ
Scylla was you.
You helped the separatist army,
then faked your death.
独立軍を支援し
そして 死を偽装した
You helped the separatist army,
then faked your death.
その後 お前が指導したゲリラは
皆殺しだ
Later, the guerillas you led were all killed.
思い出したくもねえ作戦だろうよ
I can see why you wouldn't
want to remember that op.
それ以来 頻繁な義体乗り換えは
やめたわ
Since then, I've stopped
switching bodies so often.
自己喪失に襲われるのよ
It gives me an identity crisis.
I lose track of who I am...
自分が何者か分からなくなって…
It gives me an identity crisis.
I lose track of who I am...
誰かに自分はロボットではないと
教えてほしくなる
...and then I want someone
to tell me I'm not a robot.
（バトー）量産ベースの―
/s that why you insist on making original
tweaks to your mass-production bases?
オリジナル･チューンナップに
こだわる理由か
/s that why you insist on making original
tweaks to your mass-production bases?
It's amazing you even managed to control
so many bod/es in such a short' time-
短期間で いくつも義体を
操れたこと自体 驚異的だぜ
It's amazing you even managed to control
so many bod/es in such a short' time-
（素子）
少し眠るわ 帰っていいのよ
I'm going to sleep a I/tt/e. You can go.
（バトー）
義体ものの よしみさ
Call it' cyborg solidarity.
おかしな部品を使われねえよう
監視してやる
/'// keep watch and make sure they
don't fit you with any sketchy parts-
（素子）そう 好きにしなさい
All right', suit yourself
（バトー）
ハァ ありがとうぐらい言え
You could at least say "thanks"!
The bullet at the scene was fired
from the lieutenant's gun.
現場の弾丸は警部補の銃から
発射されたものです
The bullet at the scene was fired
from the lieutenant's gun.
水城刑事の銃も彼の自宅から発見
I also found Mizuki's weapon
at the lieutenant's home.
そして 口座に多額の振り込み
There was a huge deposit into his account, too.
（部長）うむ… ご苦労
Good work. You can go.
帰っていいぞ
（ドアの開く音）
ふあっ ああっ…
（素子）
同業の逮捕は恨みを買うわよ
Arresting a fellow cop will
make you some enemies.
地元の警察に背後から撃たれるぞ
You'll be shot from behind
by the guys at his local.
せいぜい背中に気をつけますよ
I'll be sure to watch my back.
Did you come just to say that?
それを言いに わざわざ？
私の部隊に来ないか？
Will you join my team?
It's an independent offensive
unit with top priority.
（素子）
独立攻性最優先ラインの…
It's an independent offensive
unit with top priority.
Oh, excuse me.
あ… 失礼
Hello?
What?! I thought it'd be another two weeks!
何だって！？
（素子）あ？
What?! I thought it'd be another two weeks!
（トグサ）２週間後じゃ…？
あっ いや 分かった
すぐに行く
No, sorry, got it. I'll be right there.
This is big! Her water broke!
大変なんです は… 破水したって
Huh?
We're gonna have a baby!
生まれるんですよ 子供が
待ってろよ すぐ行くからな！
Just wait, I'll be right there!
話は また改めて
We'll talk another time.
I'm coming now!
今 行くぞ！
Natural, married, and a father?
生身で既婚者…
子持ちだと？ フフッ
Natural, married, and a father?
A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release